# MATTHEW MACLEOD

# CURRICULUM VITAE



+44 7976 121 482



matt@umm.io



www.umm.io



29 Pevensey Road London E7 OAR

### **ABOUT ME**

I'm a cross-platform software engineer with over ten years of commercial experience.

Most of my time is spent building complex publicfacing web applications, using both my computer science and graphic design experience to create compelling full-stack solutions. However, I've got extensive experience building a huge variety of other systems: low-level hardware management software, user interfaces for hardware devices, high-throughput data processing pipelines, and native mobile & desktop applications.

I've worked in a variety of mostly agile environments both as an engineer and as a technical lead managing teams of up to ten developers. I'm comfortable working to design scalable technical architectures, as well as in client-facing roles involving requirement mapping and roadmapping.

I enjoy working at all levels of the stack, but I'm particularly keen on finding a role that will allow me to combine my extensive large-scale architecture experience with the design and implementation of compelling use experiences.

## TECHNICAL SKILLSET

#### **RUBY**

I have expert knowledge of Ruby and most common frameworks and libraries, including Rails and Sinatra, and have built dozens of Ruby applications.

#### **JAVASCRIPT**

Expert Javascript knowledge on both client and server side. Experience with jQuery, Backbone, React, Ember, Express. Coffeescript, ES6/7 and Typescript advocate.

#### **HTML AND CSS**

Expert knowledge of cross-browser CSS, Sass, Less and Compass. Particular skills with high-performance responsive front-end work. Use of common libraries e.g. Bootstrap and Foundation.

#### **OBJECTIVE C**

Extenstive experience building Mac desktop apps and iOS apps. Thorough knowledge of the Cocoa and Cocoa Touch APIs.

#### GO

Good experience building highperformance networking applications using Go and popular libraries.

#### **PYTHON**

Moderate experience building and maintaining Python apps using commong libraries and frameworks (e.g. Django and Flask).

#### C/C++

Moderate experience with C, building apps to BSD API and extending Ruby and Python with C; some experience with C++ and Qt development

#### PHP

Basic experience developing and extending PHP apps (Joomla, Drupal, Wordpress, CakePHP)

# **PORTFOLIO**

projects.ac
altmetric.com
parkcircus.com
glasgowfilm.org
arthritiscare.org.uk
scottishrefugeecouncil.org.uk
theskinny.co.uk
morleycollege.ac.uk

#### **JAVA**

Moderate experience building server/ desktop apps in Java, and Android apps on Dalvik.

#### **TESTING**

Full knowledge of a variety of testing suites: rspec, test\_unit/minitest, Cucumber, mocha, XCTest.

#### **DATABASES**

Implementation, management and optimisation for MySQL, PostgreSQL, Sqlite, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Redis, InfluxDB.

#### **DEVOPS**

Linux server management and cloud deployment with Capistrano and Chef. Experience building and using Docker images and other containerisation tools.

#### **PROCESS**

Git/SVN/Hg experience. Management of CI servers and continuous integration and delivery.

#### **PROJECT MANAGEMENT**

Extensive work with Jira, Pivotal Tracker, Trello, Trac. Knowledge of main Agile and Scrum principles.

#### **DESIGN AND PRODUCTION**

PDF, PostScript, colour management systems and TIFF/JPEG and other image formats. Expert knowledge of all major graphic design tools, including Adobe Photoshop, Indesign and Illustrator. Extensive knowledge of graphic design principles and techniques.

#### **USER EXPERIENCE**

Commercial experience designing and building compelling user interfaces for a wide variety of applications.

festmag.co.uk
goodmoves.org.uk/mobile
refugeecouncil.org.uk
williamtraceygroup.com
finalfling.com
intralink.biz
yourfuneraldirectors.co.uk
github.com/mattmacleod

# MATTHEW MACLEOD

## CURRICULUM VITAE

## **EDUCATION**

#### **UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH CLASS OF 2007**

MASTER OF ENGINEERING (MEng) 2:1 HONOURS, ELECTRONICS & COMPUTER SCIENCE An interdepartmental computer science and engineering degree which covers the entire spectrum of computer systems, including hardware and processor design, algorithms, languages, data structures and user interfaces.

## PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **DIGITAL SCIENCE. 2013-CURRENT**

Digital Science is the skunkworks arm of Holtzbrinck Publishing, and focuses on getting new technology into the hands of scientists, labs and research institutions across the world. I initially worked on the laboratory data management product **Projects**, where I implemented the research and development of a ground-up re-write as a native desktop application for Mac OS. I then transitioned to the **Altmetric** team, where I led the redesign and implementation of several large-scale, public-facing web applications and backend processing systems. Throughtout my time here, I've also worked on the implementation of infrastructure improvements and various other internal applications.

#### **TECHNICAL DIRECTOR**

#### **TICTOC, 2009-2013**

Tictoc is a middleweight digital agency who develop websites and web/mobile apps for a diverse client base, with over 300 live projects for charities, educational institutions and private businesses. I developed the technical platforms we used to deliver projects, with the goal of providing a developer-focused toolset allowing high-quality output with quick turnarounds. This included the development of a new, flexible in-house framework on top of Rails targeted at rapid application development, exploiting technologies including Sass, Haml, Coffeescript and PJAX. I introduced TDD and agile practices to the development studio, and managed the day-to-day operation of the technical team.

#### **CREATIVE DIRECTOR**

#### **RADGE MEDIA, 2007-2009**

Radge Media is the publisher of UK culture magazine *The Skinny*. As the Creative Director, I managed design and layout for the monthly magazine as well as frequent special publications. I later moved to head up the company's digital strategy, and developed a powerful bespoke platform for cross-channel online and print magazine publishing. This project included complex data management tools and integration with multiple third-party data sources, with the ability to cross-publish between web and mobile apps while integrating with Adobe InDesign for print publishing. I also developed a number of other in-house applications and data management tools.

#### **MANAGING DIRECTOR**

#### **THE JOURNAL, 2007-2009**

I launched a local newspaper publisher in partnership with a small group of colleagues. I oversaw the strategy and leadership of the business, created the company's branding, and produced the biweekly print editions of the newspaper. I built custom workflow management software which was integrated with external content providers, using XML to provide a unified storage layer with transforms for online and print publishing.

#### **CREATIVE DIRECTOR**

#### **FEST MAGAZINE, 2004-2014**

Fest is an annual magazine which publishes reviews of shows at the Edinburgh Festival. I designed and produced six print issues each year over three weeks, and managed the publication's brand and marketing materials. I also developed the magazine's website, which cross-references several third-party data feeds to provide real-time geolocated information about nearby events to mobile users.